Guide to the Papers of Peter Koch, 1974-2003 M1584
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series IV. JOB FILES, CHRONOLOGICAL
  - Job files, miscellaneous, various dates
    - Camp and Hotels, etc. travel; #1415 (Carton 20)
    - Frankfurt Bunchmesse (pamphlets/brochures); #1394 (Carton 20)
    - Estimates; #1393 (Carton 20)
    - History of the Book Colloquia; #1389 (Carton 20)
    - Deborah Oropallo Project (Carton 20)
    - Skidmore, Owings, and Merrill (Christmas Invitation) (Carton 20)
    - Russian Thackrey (Carton 20)
    - Shiramizu Business System II, 1993 (Carton 20)
    - Sean Thackey Eps (Carton 20)
    - Orion, 1993 (Carton 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985; #800 (Carton 21)
    - Franklin Furnace Inquiry, 1989; #801 (Carton 21)
    - Apprentices, 1993; #802 (Carton 21)
    - Stransky, 2005; # (Carton 21)
    - Filter / moving card; #1302 (Carton 21)
    - Susan Filter; #1343 (Carton 21)
    - Susan Filter; #1342 (Carton 21)
    - Breakfast Poem; #1311 (Carton 21)
    - Missoula Museum, 2002 (Carton 21)
    - Holter Museum Auction 2003 (Carton 21)
    - Bus Expenses (Carton 21)
    - Rox Club - April Meeting Announcement 2006 (Carton 21)
    - Karl Hentzog Award 2006 (Carton 21)
    - Matt Phillips / Song of Solomon 2006 (Carton 21)
    - Bookplate Keepsake BCC 2005 (Carton 21)
    - Florida St. Divider, 1981, #789 (Carton 21)
    - Checklist of Items in New York Public Library Collection, #790 (Carton 21)
    - Invitation to Join International Association of Bibliophiles, 1979?, #791 (Carton 21)
    - Stanford University - Adam Repon Petko Type Collection Assessment, 1995, #803 (Carton 21)
    - Book Club Quarterly Bid 1994-97 (Carton 21)
    - Gleeson Library Associates Spring Tour Announcement 1987 (Carton 21)
    - Ernest Peninou 1994, 1995 (Carton 21)
    - Christopher Benson Studio 1995 (Carton 21)
    - Jane Wilson Memorial Invitation 1993 (Carton 21)
    - Missoula Libraries Exhibit 1993 (Carton 21)
    - MILLS Conference 1993 (Carton 21)
    - Correspondence 1979-1982 Robert Blesse Librarian, #792 (Carton 21)
    - Consignment 1980, #793 (Carton 21)
    - Orders for Books 1981, #794 (Carton 21)
    - PK @ UC Berkeley Library School (briefly a grad student) 1982, #795 (Carton 21)
    - Diana Adams (Carton 21)
    - 2005: Correspondence/ U of M Library Frank DAndrea etc; Montana/Letter to Accompany U R text vol. III (Carton 21)
    - Misc. Correspondence (1) (Carton 21)
    - Misc. Correspondence (2) (Carton 21)
- Series V. ALPHABETICAL CORRESPONDENCE
  Alphabetical by name of correspondent.
  - Acosta, Juvenal; Adams, Diana; Allen, Susan; Aguire, Carlos; Allen, Lewis; Allen, Terry; Amert, Kay; Anderson, Kent; Antin, Eleanor; Auster, Paul; Babcock, Jon; Ballard, J. G.; Barsamian, Astrid (1); Barsamian, Astrid (2). (Carton 21)
  - Bartkowiak; Barton, Carol; Berman, Hannah; Bleitz, Karen; Borneman; Bowles, Bea; Braun, Steve; Bringhurst, Robert; Butler, Francis; Butler, Jan; Calabrese, Bianca; Camp, Jim; Campbell, Carole; Carr/Ferrari (1); Carr/Ferrari (2); Carson, Gary (NO LABEL ON FOLDER); Charlo, Victor; Churchman, Carol; Ciabattari, Mark; Cicale, Ann; Conrad, Lisa; Corey, Steve; Cornford, Adam; Cowell, Anne; Coyote, Peter; Dal Poggetto, Sandra; Dillon, Richard; Decamp, Susan; Dobb, Edwin; Doig, Ivan; Dunsmore, Roger; Elsted, Crispin; Ely, Tim; Everson, William; Everts, Edwina; Fetter-Vorm, Jonathan; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence; Filter, Susan; Flanagan, Daniel; Fraser, Carolyn; Friedman, Phyllis; Frost, Gary; Frym, Gloria; Garcia, Annick; Gentry, L. (Carton 22)
  - Gifford, Barry; Girvin, Tim; Goines, David; Goldyne, Joseph; Grahm, Lonnie; Greenwood, Gorgianna; Grolier Club; Hamady, Walter; Hays, Susannah; Hellyer, George/ Ira Yeager; Higgins, Dick; Holtan, Gene; Hostetler, Susan; Hodgson, Heather; Hubregtse, Sjaak; Jenkins, Joyce; Johnson, Brice; Johnston, Alastar; Kane, Colleen; Keeler, Greg; Kumataka, Jan; Kuznicki, Philip; Landenberger, Brett; Laws, Dick; Leake, C.D.; Logan, David; Logue, Chris; Maclay, Sarah; Maclean, Norman; Magee, Jennifer; Maret, Russell,; Marlis, Stephanie; McFadden, Cyra; Mears, Allen; Merker, Kim; Merwin, W.S.; Milevsky, Maureen; Mitchell, Steven; Monihan, Wiliam; Mustain, John; Nelson, Keiko; Newby, Rick; Newman, Stephine; Novak, Rev. David Alan; Owens, Kathy (Carton 23)
  - Parrenson, Driel (correspondence); Peoples, Dave and Jan; Peterson, Greg; Phillips, Jenna; Paoge, Mike; Paoge, Mike; Porter, Elliot; Private Press Books; Price, Robin; Quezada, Andrea; Real Bird, Hank; Reese, Harry; Risseevw, John; Ritchie, George F; Rivera, Elena; Rivera, Gustavos Ramos; Robertson, Joyce; Roether, Susan; Rummonds, Gabe; Sackner, Marvin; Sanchez, Thomas; Schanilec, Gaylord; Semonin, Paul "Violet Ray"; Sharafian, Steve; Simard, Gorden; Smith, Daniel; Smith, Liz; Snyder, Susan; Stauffacher Correspondence; Spelker, Rich; Steen, Lee; Stephenson, Jonathan; Stinehour, Christepher; Stranksy, O.; Struckman, Tom; Stults, Rachel; Sykes, Jill; Taipale, Ann; Tanner, Marcia; Thomas, Dave; Twin Rocker; Valaoritis, Nanos; VanSickle, Dirk; Van Vliet, Claire; VonDemBusche, Wolf; Von Zelowitz, Jon (Carton 24)
  - Waddell, Ted and Betty; Walkup, Kathy; Weiner, Iris; Whitehill, Theresa; Whitehill, Theresa; Whiteman, Bruce; Wilkson, Jenny; Wilson, Joyce; Wurth, Michele; Wyer, Bill; You, YaoFen; Zarzyski, Paul; Zuber, Larry (Carton 25)
- Series VI. CORRESPONDENCE, MISCELLANEOUS
  Arranged chronologically for the most part.
  - Miscellaneous, 2004 Name Cards and Misc. Correspondence (Carton 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1975 (Carton 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1975 (Carton 25)
  - Miscellaneous, Prof. Corr. Misc., 1986-1995 (Carton 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Carton 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Carton 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1988-1990 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1990-1991 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1993-1995 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1995-1996 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1995-1996 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1995-1997 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 1996 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 2000 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 2000 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 2001 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, 2002 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, Misc. Correspondence 2003 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, Misc. Correspondence 2004 (Carton 25)
  - Chronological files, Misc. Correspondence 2006 (Carton 25)
- Series VII. MEDIA
  Hard drive. CLOSED WHILE BEING PROCESSED.
  - Audiotape: Peter Koch Interview, Home Ground Radio, 2004 (Carton 29)
  - Audiotape: Kantor Lecture, March 18, 2000 (Carton 29)
  - Audiotape: "Inkslinging in San Francisco, post-Grabhorn" 9 October 1989 (Carton 29)
  - CD: (two discs) Exhibition of Greek Philosophers, Book Club of CA (Carton 29)
  - DVD: "Future of Hand-Printed Books" (Carton 29)
  - VHS: Koch SFPL 1995 (Carton 29)
  - VHS: Peter Koch Interview, 9-8-2001, filmed by Seonaid B. Campbell, Missoula, MT (Carton 29)
  - Hard drive (MAC)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    CLOSED WHILE BEING PROCESSED.
- Series VIII. DATEBOOKS, PLANNERS, ETC.
  - Notebook, Europe 1997 (Carton 29)
  - Notebook, NY LA 96/98, NYC Wash., D.C. (Carton 29)
  - Notebook, 1989-90 notes (Carton 29)
  - Publishing Ledger (Carton 29)
  - Addresses, 1970s (Carton 29)
  - Unlabeled telephone list (Carton 29)
  - Telephones and misc. (Carton 29)
  - Address books 1987 (Carton 29)
  - Address books 1992 week-at-a-glance (Carton 29)
  - Planner 2001 (Carton 29)
  - Planner 1990 (Carton 29)
  - Planner 2003 (Carton 29)
  - Appointments 2000 (Carton 29)
  - Unlabeled month planner (Carton 29)
  - Week-at-a-glance 1983-4 (Carton 29)
  - Week-at-a-glance 1984-5 (Carton 29)
  - Appointment Books, 1985-2006; 2006 is in two volumes (Carton 30)
- Series IX. REVIEWS, AWARDS, ROXBURGH CLUB
  - Zebra Noise Review (Carton 31)
  - Peter Koch New Poems (Carton 31)
  - Reno Proposal (Carton 31)
  - Wm Morris/Roatcap (sp?) (Carton 31)
  - 1998 ephemera (Carton 31)
  - 1997 ephemera (Carton 31)
  - 1996 ephemera and Sale (Carton 31)
  - Ephemera checklist 1995 (packing list) (Carton 31)
  - Clark Lib. Talk/LA 2000 (Carton 31)
  - Fishing Printing: essay, pk 2000 corrected (Carton 31)
  - Stanford Article 2001 (Carton 31)
  - Buffalo Rome/Another Un-realized Adventure! (Carton 31)
  - Type Proofs of Koch Collection ca. 2003 (Carton 31)
  - Type Specimen/Lable project 1996 (Carton 31)
  - Monsan Festival of the Book sept. 2000 (Carton 31)
  - Apha Awards Committee (Carton 31)
  - Artists Book Council (Carton 31)
  - Grolier Club (Carton 31)
  - Roxburghe Club (large folder enclosing several smaller files) (Carton 31)
- Series X. BOOK SALES
  - Binder, Records 1974-1995 (Carton 31)
  - True Penny Consignment (Carton 31)
  - Book Orders (filled) 1980-2 (Carton 31)
  - Delaware/Ephemera (Carton 31)
  - Daniel Slive/UCLA (Carton 31)
  - U of Pennsylvania (Carton 31)
  - John Bidwell, Princeton University (Carton 31)
  - Scripps College (Carton 31)
  - Stanford Ephemera 1996 (Carton 31)
  - M. Garrett/U Utah (Carton 31)
  - Vincent Giroud, Yale (Carton 31)
  - UPS Claim (Carton 31)
  - SFPL Store (Carton 31)
  - Granary Books/Consignment (Carton 31)
  - SPD Consignment, McEvilley: Diogenes 3/95 (Carton 31)
  - Califia Consignment (Carton 31)
  - Inquiries/Prospectus (Carton 31)
  - Bertholf - List (Carton 31)
  - Lee Perren Consignment (Carton 31)
  - John Windle Consignment (Carton 31)
  - Consignment (Carton 31)
  - Addresses/Follow up (Carton 31)
  - Misc. Addresses, Follow-ups, etc. (Carton 31)
  - Students/Addresses (Carton 31)
  - Addresses/Send prospectus, etc. (Carton 31)
  - Addresses/Rare Books etc. (Carton 31)
  - [Printing Conference, Addresses] (unlabeled folder) (Carton 31)
  - Mailing List (Carton 31)
  - PCBA Mailing List (Carton 31)
  - RBMS [rare books and manuscripts] Addresses (Carton 31)
  - Mailing Lists for Cat[alog] (Carton 31)
  - Colophon Club (Carton 31)
- Series XI. POEMS AND ESSAYS ABOUT KOCH
  - Peter Koch, Printer/Editions Koch (Carton 32)
  - Bibliography of Peter Koch (Carton 32)
  - Missoulian Entertainer, August 11-17, 2000 (Carton 32)
  - Friday Missoulian, August 11, 2000 (Carton 32)
  - Borrowed Times, December 1975 (Carton 32)
  - Montana Kaimin, November 26, 1976 (Carton 32)
  - The San Francisco Phoenix (Carton 32)
  - Poetry Flash, August 1989 (Carton 32)
  - Missoula Independent, March 24-26, 2005 (Carton 32)
  - Missoulian Entertainer, March 17-23, 2005 (Carton 32)
  - Western Books 1980 (Carton 32)
  - ARS Typographia, List 16, Fine Printing, URSUS Rare Books (Carton 32)
  - From Papyrus to Digitalm UCIs Thesauraus of Ancient Greek Texts (Carton 32)
  - Madame, Mode Visionen (Carton 32)
  - Aldebarn Review No. 2 (Carton 32)
  - Litmus Loadstone (Carton 32)
  - Pacific Northwestern Spiritual Poetry (Carton 32)
  - Koch Lecture Invitations, etc. (Carton 32)
  - Neon Artcetera from the Nevada Arts Council, Summer 2003 (Carton 32)
  - Amphora, June 2007 (Carton 32)
  - Artist Book Council Letter (Carton 32)
  - The Bancroft Library, Fall Calendar of Events Exhibtions, 1999 (Carton 32)
  - FABS Symposium May, 21, 2005 (Carton 32)
  - Frederic W. Goudy Lecture Series on the Book Arts Buffalo Rome or Fine Printing in the Real West, November 21, 1998 (Carton 32)
  - Print News, Words As Images, August/September 1981 (Carton 32)
  - Books Extensions A Book Arts Symposium, May 1990 (Carton 32)
  - Letter Arts Review, 1995 (Carton 32)
  - Print, November/December 1995 (Carton 32)
  - Print News, Words As Images, August/September 1981 (Carton 32)
  - Fine Books Collections, September/October 2004 (Carton 32)
  - San Francisco Chronicle Magazine, September 9, 2001 (Carton 32)
  - The Threepenny Review, Summer 1999 (Carton 32)
  - Art on Paper, July-August 1999 (Carton 32)
  - Woodwork A Magazine for All Woodworkers, June 1999 (Carton 32)
  - State of the Arts California Arts Council, April 1979 (Carton 32)
  - Montana Arts, Spring 1977 (Carton 32)
  - Contemporary Fine Arts, The Art of the Book: Treasures from the Bay Area, 2005 (Carton 32)
  - Yellowstone Art Museum, Annual Report 2003-2004 (Carton 32)
  - College of Environmental Design (CED) News, Spring 1995 (Carton 32)
  - Retrospective at The New York Public Library of an Eclectic Printers Career, Peter Koch, Printer: Cowboy Surrealists, Maverick Poets, Pre-Socratic Philosophers, 1994-5 (Carton 32)
  - Point Lobos in Poem and Photograph, November 26, 1988 (Carton 32)
  - First International Miniprint Exhibition, 1991 (Carton 32)
  - Books Extensions - A Book Arts Symposium (Carton 32)
  - Amphora - 93, The Quarterly Journal of the Alcuin Society, Autumn 1993 (Carton 32)
  - The 58th Annual Western Books Exhibition, 1999 (Carton 32)
  - The 63rd Annual Western Books Exhibition, 2004 (Carton 32)
  - The Modern Coil, August 2006, The Small Press (Carton 32)
  - The Book Club of California Quarterly News-Letter, Winter 1994 (Carton 32)
  - The Book Club of California Quarterly News-Letter, Winter 2000 (Carton 32)
  - The Book Club of California Quarterly News-Letter, Spring 1989 (Carton 32)
  - Gallery 16 Editions 1994-2001 (Carton 32)
  - Collaborations and Connections: 20th Century Collaborative Bookworks (Carton 32)
  - The Book Club of California Quarterly News-Letter, Winter 2000 (Carton 32)
  - The Book Club of California Quarterly News-Letter, Winter 1994 (Carton 32)
  - The Montclarion, Old-fashioned printing still thriving, January 12, 1988 (Carton 32)
  - Eight Years: The Editions of Gallery 16 prints, artist books, multiples (Poster) (Carton 32)
  - Westward Bound An Exhibition Celebrating Book Arts in the West (Carton 32)
  - Westward Bound An Exhibition Celebrating Book Arts in the West (Carton 32)
  - GLA Newsletter #27, Peter Rutledge Koch, Printer, Summer 1994 (Carton 32)
- Series XII. DIRK LEE ARCHIVE, Lee, Dirk
  - Dirk Lee letters, 2007 (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee postcards (15) (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee prints (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee personal (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee letters 1979-1986 (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee letters 1987-1990 (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee letters 1991-1993 (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee letters 1994-1995 (Carton 33)
  - Dirk Lee letters 1996-1998, undated (Carton 33)
- Series XIII. STUDENT WORK
  - Student work (Carton 34)
- Series XIV. BOOK ARCHIVES
  Scope and Contents note
  Material relating to specific book projects; folders may contain correspondence, notes, articles, paste-up dummies, proofs, prospectus and drafts (computer printouts). Series is arranged by project number. Each group of material includes a listing of materials by Koch that were in the archive (photocopy).
  This Sub-series is only partially processed. The remainder is CLOSED UNTIL RE-HOUSED AND DESCRIBED.
  - Project #718: On Printing by William Everson, 1992 (Box 35)
  - Project #718 continued: contains galleys, photographs, printing plates, etc. (Box 36)
  - Project #718 continued: camera ready copy and film, mock-up, etc. (Flat-box 37)
  - Project #718 continued: bluelines and layouts (Map-folder 38)
  - Project #719: Personal, poems by Robert Creeley with prints by John Millei; includes display sheets, Millei proofs, etc. (Box 36)
  - Project #719 continued: Millei proofs (early states), sheets (unfolded), article, poster, layout chart, etc. (Flat-box 37)
  - Project #719 continued: Millei proof (various states), foundry proof (some pages with notes by Creeley), title page negative and plate, etc. (Box 39)
  - Project #720: Unsought Intimacies by Thomas Gunn with illustrations by Theopolis Brown, 1994; includes invitation; press; film, darwings and plate for cover, etc. (Box 40)
  - Project #721: Unsought Intimacies continued: page proofs (annotated), paste-ups, folded stock (quartos), etc. (Box 40)
  - Project #722: Would You Like to Saddle Up a Couple of Goldfish and Swim to Alaska? by Richard Brautgou, printed by Koch and Bancroft Library class, 1995; includes original notebook (photocopy), proof (quarots), etc. (Box 40)
  - Project #722 continued (Flat-box 37)
  - Project #722 continued: collage (original and photocopy), faxes with B. Weiss, cover sketches and negatives, etc. (Box 41)
  - Project #723: Diogenes: Defictions archive I - research: notebook (disbound), list (Box 41)
  - Project #724: Diogenes archive II - production, printing, defictions: type samples (photocopy), Carol Twombley correspondence, box art and proofs, booklet art and proofs, plates, etc. (Box 41)
  - Project #725: Diogenes archives III - book, correspondence, etc.: handwritten draft, McEvilley text, various drafts, receipts, film, 3 1/2" floppies (2), plates, etc. (Box 42)
  - Project #725 continued: camera ready copy, film, printers drawings on tracepaper, etc. (Flat-box 43)
  - Project #726: Soul of the Vine: Wine in Literature; re Robert Mondavi Winery, edited by Nina Wemyss, illustrated by Margrit Biever, 2nd edition, 1990: receipts with estimates, sample cloth and stock, etc. (Box 42)
  - Project #726 continued: foundry proofs with notes (4) (Map-folder 44)
  - Project #726 continued: printers proofs (Flat-box 45)
  - Project #727: Soul of the Vine continued: promotional material, printers drawings on tracepaper and layout, etc. (Flat-box 43)
  - Project #727 continued: page proofs, proof on stock (unfolded) (Flat-box 45)
  - Project #727 continued: list with notes, receipts, drawings (photocopies), book plates, various proofs, etc. (Box 46)
  - Project #727 continued: foundry proofs (Map-folder 47)
  - Project #728: The Fragments of Herakleitos, translated by Guy Davenport, 1990: printers layout on tracepaper, etc. (Flat-box 43)
  - Project #728 continued: correspodnence with Guy Davenport, Cy Twombly, Jennifer Garden, etc.; receipts, orders, etc. (Box 46)
  - Project #728 continued: type samples, etc. (Box 48)
  - Project #729: Fragments continued (Flat-box 43)
  - Project #729 continued (Box 48)